

JEANACLARK

228 Catalpa Road, Apt. #3 • Lexington, Kentucky 40502 • 859.553.1426 • jeana@jeanaclark.org

STRENGTHS

Creative and innovative graphic designer who collaborates with organizations and companies to help them tell their unique and inspiring story.

Over 12 years print media design, with 10 years in web development • Translates marketing objectives and client needs into effective, targeted solutions applying all aspects of identity development, visual storytelling, print and web design • Designs brands, logos, brochures, advertisements, catalogs, and magazines through all phases of development from concept to final execution

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Print & Web Designer - Lexington, KY - 1996-Present

Works independently and with in-house art directors to complete projects ahead of schedule and within budget constraints

- Designs branding and identity systems, produces magazines, bound books and book covers, and builds web sites for higher-education and non-profit organizations
- Creates 3-D environments within Second Life for Abraham Paiss & Associates, a non-profit firm promoting sustainable development
- Partial Client List: Anglican District of Virginia, Asbury College, Asbury Theological Seminary, CANA, Cre8tive Group, Etopia EcoVillage, and Jessamine County Victim Advocate Office

Graphic Designer = Follett Educational Distribution Group = Lexington, KY = 2007-09

Produced over 75 print and web projects annually for seven divisions of the Follett Corporation. Projects include: logos, sell-sheets, brochures, stationery, direct-mail collateral, magazines, catalogs, web sites, and trade-show signage

- Maintained individual branding standards for seven Follett divisions while producing new and successful design concepts
- Developed "Delighting the Customer" and "Ignite Delight" branding initiatives for internal employee appreciation program including the design of email blasts, intranet site, and various promotional and printed items
- Branded three national sales meetings and produced accompanying collateral, PowerPoint slides, notepads, name badges, signage, and invitations
- Designed new national ad campaign for Follett Library Resources, including seven new ads
- Maintained ad specifications for Follett Software Company, Follett Educational Services, and Follett Library Resources resizing, revising, and editing existing ads to be placed in eight national publications
- Coordinated with BWI marketing department and copywriters to design and produce, TitleTalk, a 24-page public library resource magazine, reaching over 10,000 librarians
- Supervised and art-directed two freelance designers on various print and web projects

Lead Graphic Designer = Asbury Theological Seminary = Wilmore, KY = 2006-07

Designed materials for the admission, development, student life, and academic offices and oversaw the printing process from initial estimates, bidding, design, proofing to final delivery. Projects delivered on time and within budget

- Rebranded the Beeson Institute Scholarship program, including all design and copywriting for website and national advertisement campaign
- Art-directed and produced three issues of *The Asbury Herald*, reaching an audience of 18,000
 alumni and donors; made artistic decisions based on magazine content, produced original art
 work, and directed photography



JEANACLARK

228 Catalpa Road, Apt. #3 Lexington, Kentucky 40502 859.553.1426 jeana@jeanaclark.org

EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

Graphic Designer - Asbury Theological Seminary - Wilmore, KY - 2005-06

Collaborated with senior designer and copywriter to produce materials for the admission, development, student life, and academic offices

- Designed and produced four 100+ page devotional guides and a 200+ page academic catalog
- · Created identities and collateral for alumni conferences and major-donor retreats
- · Oversaw the printing process from initial estimates, bidding, design, proofing to final delivery

Production Assistant = Asbury Theological Seminary = Wilmore, KY = 2004-05

Under the direction of the senior designer, created materials for the admission, development, student life, and academic offices

- Provided editorial and production support to The Asbury Theological Journal, including typesetting, copyfitting, and publication management, a biannual publication reaching over 1,500 theologians
- Functioned as technical support to the Mac-based office; troubleshooting, software updates, and hardware upgrades

Communications Assistant = Asbury Theological Seminary = Wilmore, KY = 2002-04

Directed Student Life communications, including the design, photography, printing, and distribution of all web and print materials for the department

- Designed, maintained, wrote and distributed a weekly campus calendar and newsletter, highlighting weekly events and incorporating stories from around campus
- Incorporated aspects of the seminary brand in all student life publications
- Created and maintained a student web portal using a content management system, HTML, & CSS

Web Developer & Customer Service Specialist = Multiservice Corporation = Overland Park, KS = 2001Collaborated with a team of PERL programmers to code nostalgia and gaming store-front web sites using standards-compliant HTML & CSS

 Increased product sales by 40% with effective web site redesign and prompt technical and customer support

Assistant Graphic & Web Designer = Southwestern College = Winfield, KS = 2000-01

Produced creative marketing materials in collaboration with senior designers, projects included brochures, business cards, newsletters, and theatre publicity

- · Wrote press releases and ad copy for various college departments
- Redesigned and maintained historical web site about one room school houses

SKILLS

Adobe CS4 = Adobe InDesign = Adobe Photoshop = Adobe Illustrator = Adobe Acrobat QuarkXPress = Mac & PC Platforms = Microsoft Office Suite HTML = CSS

HONORS

Kansas Associated Collegiate Press Awards • Web site design and news writing Presidential Scholar & Salgo-Noren Study Abroad Scholarship Recipient Who's Who Among American College Students

EDUCATION

Master of Arts, Biblical Studies = Asbury Theological Seminary = Wilmore, KY = 2005 Bachelor of Arts, English = Southwestern College = Winfield, KS = 2000



Follett Library Resources Product Logo



Follett Library Resources & BWI

Joint National Sales Meeting Logo + Identity



Golden Tree Academy Branding & Logo



Follett Software Company

Sales Campaign Logo





Follett Educational Services Online services logo & icons